Guide to the Jack Lewis papers, 1915-2001.
Lewis, Jack papers,
- Cornell United Religious Works (CURW)
  - Subseries IIe. Social Programs
    - Clergy Consultation Service correspondence and notes, 1969-1973 (Box 50, Folder 2-3)
      Access restrictions apply.
    - Drug prevention, 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 10-11)
    - Awareness training, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Subseries IIf. Speaking Engagements, Workshops, and Conferences Files
    - Lubbock, Texas, 1978-05 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Speaking engagements: past, 1965-1980 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Speaking engagements: declined, 1965-1972 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Speaking engagements, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Speaking engagements: future, 1972-1978 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Racism seminar, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Alcoholism and family, Sage Chapel and lecture, 1975-1979 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Beech Hill Pond Meditation Center, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - ACURA, 1975-1981 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Fall campus conference on religion, 1980-11 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Speaking engagements: alumni groups, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - American Cancer Society, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Notebooks on alcohol workshop and centennial symposia, 1965-04-1965-05 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Quebec City safety discussion group, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Austin College, Sherman Texas, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Schreiner College, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Evelyn Wood: Reading Dynamics, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 38-39)
    - Dialogue House, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - California trip: crisis intervention, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Subseries IIg. Resource Files
    Include program information, publications, and mailers.
    - Howard Blake: Laity, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Reference articles, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Recovery, Inc., 1977 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Emotions anonymous, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Great Issues course, 1967-09 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Reference papers and reports, 1967-1970 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
    - CURW and Ithaca history booklets, 1960-1980 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Work and Study Resource Files
  This series contains a mix of documents that were grouped together in steel file drawers and boxes. Some may relate to CFLC or CURW.
  - Genesis study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Exodus study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Leviticus study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Numbers study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Deuteronomy study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Joshua study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Judges study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Ruth study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - I Samuel study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - II Samuel study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - I Kings study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - II Kings study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - I Chronicles study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - II Chronicles study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Ezra study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Jeremiah study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Esther study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Job study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Psalms study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Proverbs study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Isaiah study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Jeremiah study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Lamentations study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Ezekiel study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Hosea study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Jonah study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Micah study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Haggai study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Matthew study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Mark study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Luke study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - John study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Acts study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Romans study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - I Corinthians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - II Corinthians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Galatians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Philippians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Colossians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Ephesians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - I Thessalonians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - II Thessalonians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - I Timothy study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - II Timothy study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Titus study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Philemon study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Philippians study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Hebrews study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - James study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - I Peter study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - II Peter study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - I John study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - II John study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - III John study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Jude study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Revelations study material, 1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Seminary, 1933-1942 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Sermon ideas, 1932-1945 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Texts of sermons and sermon ideas, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Miscellaneous sermon files, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Talks, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - National conference of Christians and Jews, 1946-1947 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Weddings, 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Includes Lewis' license to perform marriages in Maine
  - Race material, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Conference material, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Includes church bulletins and badges from the National University Extension Convention and Louisiana Cattlemen's Convention.
  - Synod Radio, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Poetry and Prose, 1940-1950 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Evangelism, 1940-1944 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Presbytery of Northeast Texas, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Student ministry, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Mission, 1954-1957 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Role of Minister in Church, by parish ministers, 1960-03-15 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Continued minister education, 1959-10-08 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - The mood of the college student, 1959-11 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Missions- at home and abroad, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Religious workers, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Bible study, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Worship folders (churches), 1950-1960 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Ministry of the laity, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Nature of the Church, 1959-03 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Service projects for students, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Church vocations, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Chiles lay theological curriculum, 1950-1960 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Money-raising, 1950-1960 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Curriculum, 1950-1960 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Presbyterian curriculum, 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Religious set-up at UT, Undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Worship lectionary, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Lay library, Undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Conferences: church for laymen, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Student programs, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - American Friends service committee, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, Undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Religious emphasis week, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Lay work of the Evangelical Reform Church, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Presbytery seminary graduate students conference, 1959-01-03 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Orientation, Undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Methodism, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Higher education (program- Laos), 1958 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Student work, 1959-08-17 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - UT Requirements, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Articles on communism and Eastern Europe, Undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Theological articles, Undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Code of Ethics, Undated (Box 11, Folder 42)
    From Walker's Austex Chili company, and booklet from International Labor Organization.
  - Resource materials, with some correspondence, 1950-1959 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Sermon and analysis reference files, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Worship materials, 1939-1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Notes and printouts on religion, 1945-1955 (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
    May contain schoolwork.
  - Greek Exegeses, 1945-1955 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Presbytery papers, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Worship file, 1960-1975 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Experimental music ideas, 1960-1975 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Worship, 1960-1975 (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
  - William Glenesk worship file, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Divorce: ritual of release, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Step family material, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - MLK, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Kirkridge, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Sane/freeze, Undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - MLK scholarship fund, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Meditation: who dies?, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 19-20)
  - AIDS info, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Your Retirement Guide, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - PREP participant manual, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 21-22)
  - The appealing power of music, 1940-1950 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Articles on anti-semitism, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Articles on cults, 1976-1980 (Box 31, Folder 6-7)
    Includes The Way
- Social Programs
  - Subseries IV a. Alcoholism
    - Pamphlets and publications on alcoholism and Alcoholics Anonymous, 1950-1960 (Box 12, Folder 7-9)
    - Alcoholics Anonymous newsletters, 1953-1959 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Alcoholics Anonymous fact file, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Alcohol problem, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Subseries IV b. Hospital Chaplaincy and Cornell Visitation
    - Hospital Chaplain advisory committee, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Durham Trust, 1990-1998 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Durham Chaplaincy, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Chaplaincy donor list, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Durham Chaplaincy correspondence, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Durham Chaplaincy meeting agenda and documents, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Eugene Durham Chaplaincy information, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Hospicare, 1982-1991 (Box 12, Folder 20-21)
    - Hospicare, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 13-15)
    - Cornell visitation notes, 1997-06-1998-05 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Cornell Visitation information, 1987-1997 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Visitation program files, 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Cornell Visitation Program reports and files, 1995-2000 (Box 12, Folder 24-28)
    - Cornell Visitor orientation, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Massage therapy packet, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Subseries IV c. Pastoral Counseling
    - Counseling service information and notes, 1962-1982 (Box 12, Folder 31-33)
    - Pastoral consultant agreement with Cornell, 1984-1987 (Box 12, Folder 34)
      Contains Pastoral Consultant Reports.
    - Work log, 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Pastoral counseling information and notes, 1977-1995 (Box 12, Folder 36-37)
    - Prayers for pastoral care, Undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Counseling notes, pamphlets, and correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Pastoral Consultant reports, 1984-1995 (Box 13, Folder 3-9)
      Some folders may contain information on the Cornell Visitors Program.
    - Pat Short, 1980-07 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Fr. Manickhan, 1980-07-21 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Lamphere, 1980-10 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Counseling notes, 1980-12 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Caritas, Undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - University Counseling Advising Network, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Counseling workshops, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Counseling notes, 1980-06 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Draft counselees, 1980-07-15 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Counseling notes and report, 1987-1989 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Notes and documents, 1975-1985 (Box 30, Folder 25)
      Includes some wedding photographs
  - Subseries IV d. Cornell Retiree Program
    - Agendas, board meeting minutes, correspondence, 1980-2001 (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
    - Members and administration, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Bylaws and notes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Subseries IV e. Other Programs
    - Laos House, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Ithaca Zen Center, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Festival of Black Gospel 20th anniversary, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - CRESP (Center for Religion, Ethics, and Social Policy) information, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - CRESP notes from wooden box, Undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Wooden box presented to Lewis from CRESP, 1996 (Box 13)
    - CRESP, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Campus life and CURW, 1983-1984 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - MLK Jr. Association, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 24)
- Workshops, Lectures, and Sermons
  - Subseries Va. General
    Many of the folders contain church bulletins.
    - Homophobia workshop, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Disarmament, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Institute for Cultural Affairs publications, notes, and correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 21-23)
    - Institute for Cultural Affairs publications, notes, and correspondence, 1979-1984 (Box 14, Folder 27-28)
    - Conference on Christianity and His daily work, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Invocation at President Rhodes' inauguration, 1977-11-10 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Sermon: three questions about living, loving, and letting go, 1999-12 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - The Riverside Church convocation on preaching, 1978-1982-10 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Appealing power of music, Undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
      Draft.
    - Free to be Used, 1993-08-22-1999 (Box 13, Folder 29)
      Sermon given at the First Presbyterian Church of Ithaca. Also, Kendal Ecumenical Gathering.
    - Meditation from "Who Dies?", Undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous readings and notes, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Some things money can't buy service, 2001-11-4 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sermon: the spiritual dimension, 2000-11 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Hempstead and Prairie View at A+M, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Beacon Hill Presbyterian Church, San Antonio, 1964-06 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - General Assembly, Montreal, 1964-04 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Past speaking engagements, 1962-1964 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Past speaking engagements and sermons, 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Stoney Point trip, 1962-12 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Covenant Presbyterian Church, San Antonio, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Columbus Ohio meeting, 1951-1958 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Association of Presbyterian University Pastors conference, Wisconsin, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - World Council Consultation, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Danforth Campus Christian Workers conference, 1957-1959 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Europe trip, laymens training, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 16-17)
    - Miscellaneous speaking material, 1953-1968 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - North Carolina, Virginia, Washington DC, Houston, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Conference brochure, 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Panel on Quaker way, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Austin lecture trip, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - New Orleans lecture trip, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Center for World Community, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Human relations clippings, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Violence, racism, etc. notes, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Unitarian Church, "Accepting Life Unconditionally", 1985-03 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Unmarried marrieds on campus, 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 30)
      Includes clippings and articles.
    - Ideas, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Our Human Vocation: pursuit of the common good, Undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - UPC Austin reunion, 1990-04 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Tell your own story: ordination 40th anniversary, 1967-1980 (Box 14, Folder 34)
      Also includes a Sage Chapel sermon from 1967.
    - Presbyterian church sermon folder, Undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Sermon: the Christian way, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Is marriage still a viable institution?, Undated (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Parenting, 1977-05 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Ottawa workshop, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Notes for speeches, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 40)
      Includes pamphlets and brochures.
    - Sermon material, 1964-1970 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Sermons and services, 1972-1978 (Box 14, Folder 42)
      Includes church bulletins, Sage Chapel sermons, and articles.
    - Sermons and articles by others, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Jazz liturgy, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Valuing and faithing: clues to presonal identity, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Something new is coming, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Transcendent behavior, Undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Marriage enrichment seminar, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Waterloo, Canada, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Breadking the double-bind, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Ernest Bangs eternal life, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Friendship, 1978-03-14 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Article for the Daily Sun on suicide prevention, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Speech file, Undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Contains pamphlets and drafts.
    - Notes for talk, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Peace work speech folder, 1980-1982 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - A gift full of grace and truth, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - No one is exempt from the human situation, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Religion as a window on the world, 1988-08-20 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Dialogical worship: rehearsing the drama of our salvation, 1980-06-22 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Kirkridge retreat, St Paul Methodist group, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Sermons: the othering of God, vocation, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Faith and belief: St. John, 1973-03-25 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Unsorted, 1970-1980 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Includes articles, xerox copies of correspondence, and drafts.
    - Faith development process, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - CPR sermon, 1987-02 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Summer sermons and lectionary, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - From myth to parable, Undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Every family named, 1987-05-10 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Inner affinity: toward maturity and wholeness, 1970-1975 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Christ in my life: there's music, 1986-03-19 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Functional meaning and thanksgiving, 1979-11-21 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Paradoxes, 1985-06-21 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Facing changes and crises, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Sermon: how long, O Lord?, 1992-02-09 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Sermon: to be kind, 1992-11-15 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Temptation/repentence/lent, 1984-03-11 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Sermons from others, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Palm Sunday: confrontation day, 1971-04-04 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Sermon ideas, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Geo: the eye of our eyes, Undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Necessary narcissism, 1988-02-28 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Sermon on the mount: belief/behavior, 1982-09-26 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Issues of faith and life, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Life journey: an end and a beginning, 1982-1990 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Stages of faith, 1978-1989 (Box 15, Folder 41-45)
      Includes correspondence, notes,, interviews, articles, and pamphlets.
    - Lansing Methodist Church, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Sermon ideas, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Sermon at First Presbyterian Church, 2001-07-15 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Baptism ideas, Undated (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Kendall's service (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Sage Chapel service in memory of Jack Lewis, 2002-07-07 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Paul Tillich's sermon: you are accepted, Undated (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Who do people say I am?, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Beginnings without end, 1981-09-06 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Celebration of divorce, Undated (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Mason Texas Presbyterian Church bulletins and sermons, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 34-36)
    - Grace Presbyterian Church bulletins, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - St. Andrews programs, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Austin Presbyterian Theological seminary bulletin, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Local church programsn and bulletins, 1964-1979 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Grace Church, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Mission Presbytery, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Westminster Church, Austin, 1957-1959 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Agricultural Teams, Inc., 1979-1981 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Future speaking engagements, sermons, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - DNR conference, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Trumansburg inter-religion meeting, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Shalom Mountain resource packet, 1980-01-29 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - ITEST conference, 1974-10 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Margaret Gordon Munchmeyer interview, 1989-10-02 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - NTL Bethel Maine, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 10-11)
  - Subseries Vb. Sage Chapel
    Many folders contain chapel programs.
    - Law and grace, 1988-03-06 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Earnestness of being important, 1980-08-31 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - The great convergence occupation vs. vocation, 1979-01-21 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Easter material, 1972-1977 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - Habitat, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Belief in God: functional or creedal, 1971-01 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Life in face of death, 1970-10-11 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Christmas program, 1977-12-11 (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - Communion service, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - Sage Baccu sermon notes, 1969-06-08 (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - Freedom to be and become, 1972-05-21 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Situation ethics, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Sage classes, 1966-1968 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Family planning: wise and otherwise, 1979-09-02 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Behold we live, 1974-06-02 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Homecoming, yes and no, 1978-10-29 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Life of integrity, 1970-06-07 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Copies of Sage Chapel sermons, 1982-1985 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Heretic: authority to be free, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - The good Samaritan, 1987-07-05 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - 50th anniversary of ordination, 1990-07-15 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Rainbow relation and generic religion, 1984-02-12 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Creativity and longevity: the placebo effect, 1980-05-25 (Box 25, Folder 23)
- US Navy Documents
  This series was labelled by Lewis
  - Subseries Iva. Alphabetical Correspondence Files
    Includes correspondence and information on Lewis' time as Navy Chaplain.
    - Correspondence A, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence B, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence C, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence D, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence E, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence F, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence G, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence H, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence I, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence J, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence K, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence L, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence M, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence N, 1943-1946 (Box 16, Folder 25)